PERSONAL DETAILS

Availability: Immediate Phone: +32 487 49 84 83

Language: English, French, PortugueseEmail: patricialvesmarques@gmail.comLocation: Brussels, BelgiumPortfolio: behance.net/patricialvcad1

PROFILE

Expert UI / UX Designer consultant seeking contract work and immediately available for interviews in Brussels, Belgium.

2+ years of professional experience in the IT industry as UI / UX Designer using technologies such as Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD, Sketch, Zeplin, HTML5, CSS3, javascript.

My goal is to be involved with technologies and operate as expert UI / UX Designer. I am recognised as a creative person with the ability to detect code errors and always try to find the optimal solution to a problem. I believe in myself, but also believe in teamwork, so I enjoy working as part of a team. I am eager to improve organisations by adopting the latest technologies.

EMPLOYMENT SUMMARY

$December\ 2018-Till\ Date$

Tellin Shop

Status : Completed

Website : https://www.tellin.shop

Description: Appointed for wireframing and designing responsive web pages and add-ons to update an e-commerce website for a high end fashion house in Paris. Working on the Odoo framework, involved in user testing and A/B testing or the proposals before moving into production.

UX Kit

Status : Completed

Website : https://www.behance.net/gallery/74899475/ui-guidelines-for-consultancy-firm

Description: Producing a comprehensive UX Kit documentation for setting the brand's corporate identity, interaction design rules, typography, infographics, iconography as SVG and front-end UI elements - the guidelines & principles to cement the company's corporate branding. This document covers WCAG accessibility rules, CSS classes and coding guidelines to help developers implement the company's brand and structure their development work process.

Website Audit of yechte.com

Status : Completed

Website : https://yechte.com

Description: User Experience audit of the yechte website. Overall analysis of page interactions, information flow, content management, WCAG accessibility rules in line with GDPR compliance. Definition of solutions and strategies for improvement. Stakeholder management and proposals approved by the board.

April 2018 – November 2018 UI / UX Designer

RGWiT Services SPRL, Belgium

Yechte Consulting EU, Belgium

Energie Plus Le Site

Status : Under development

Website : https://www.energieplus-lesite.be/

Description: Repository website for the Architecture Department of the UCL (for "Service public de Wallonie"). This website presents an extensive collection of articles with guidelines for energy efficiency in tertiary buildings.

Being the only of its kind, it is visited frequently by architects and engineers all over the world. The Department requested a responsive website, following the graphic identity of the EPlus branding style.

MiGroup – ECI Website We Are a Welcoming Europe

Status : Completed

Website : https://weareawelcomingeurope.eu/

Description: Weareawelcomingeurope.eu is an initiative registered with the European Commission, its main objective is gathering signatures for the revision of Migration Policies in the EU. The most important feature of this website is the ECI, a petition owned by the EC, it is the fulcral point of the interface.

Automobiles Gaité

Status : Under development

Website : https://www.autosgaite.be/

Description: E-commerce website, vehicle sales for professionals. This company is based in Braine L'Alleud and has been selling Peugeot vehicles for more than two generations.

Digital Illustrations for Website

Status : Completed

Website : https://www.rgwit.be

Description: Revamped illustrations found in the website for multiple marketing materials

Customer Relationship Manager App for Yellow Pages Enterprise

Status : Under development

Description: A SAS package (Mobile App + Desktop Native App) with Small Independent Companies as target market (Contractors, Electrician, Plumbers, Gardeners, Cleaners, Truck drivers,...). The main allure of this app should be an unique User Interface and Experience where the user (35-57 yrs) can make most of the back office operations on the field, quickly and on the go.

Ogilvy - ECI Website Vaping is Not Tobacco

Status : Under development

Description: Creation of a responsive website In collaboration with Ogilvy. This website will be used to gather signatures for a petition. It is linked to wemove.eu, the petition system of the European Commission. It intends to change the regulations attached to vaping.

Socar Shipping Agency – App for Tracking Cargo Shippings

Status : Under development Website : http://socar.be

Description: SOCAR TRACKING is the application that will allow the best tracking service for all shipments with the SOCAR SHIPPING AGENCY.

Nizu - Logo Design

Status : Completed Website : http://nizu.be

Description: A logo for Nizu Core Platform Website, a branch of RGWiT Services.

June 2018 – July 2018

Birdlife International, Belgium

UI / UX Designer

Natura Alert - Logo Competition

Status : Completed

Website : http://www.birdlife.org/

App store : https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=at.ac.iiasa.naturaalert&hl=pt

Submitted work: https://www.behance.net/gallery/71282845/Logo-design-for-Natura-Alert-app

Description: Natura Alert is an app created by Birdlife International to form a community of citizens that love nature and want to contribute to the preservation of biodiversity in the natural landscape of Spain. The main feature of the app is that users can send photos and alerts in real-time to inform the Birdlife team.

April 2018 - August 2018 UI / UX Designer TRIAS, Belgium

Status : Completed

Website : https://www.trias.ngo/en/

Description: Infographics for multinational organisation TRIAS. The main requirement was the creation of a graphical element to diffuse data previously collected in an assessment report. This infographic is used as a means of starting an introspective exercise within the organisation's members.

July 2017 - Dec 2017 Designer and Sales Assistant Cozzis Casimiro Lda, Portugal

TECHNICAL AND ANALYSIS SKILLS SUMMARY

Adobe Illustrator (Expert)	Adobe Photoshop (Expert)
Adobe XD (Expert)	Zeplin (Expert)
HTML5	CSS3 & javascript
Microsoft Office 365, Slack, Skype	Google Docs & Android Style Guide
Agile "Scrum" methodology	UX tools: Sketch, Axure, InVision

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

 $\textbf{2017} \hspace{0.5cm} \textbf{Instituto Superior Tecnico} \hspace{0.1cm} | \hspace{0.1cm} \textbf{University of Lisbon} \hspace{0.1cm} | \hspace{0.1cm} \textbf{Lisbon, Portugal} \\$

Top 20 engineering schools (Shanghai Ranking, 2018)

Master Thesis in Historic Research: Multifamily housing in Lisbon during the Ancien Regime.

2016 Volunteer in a Bilingual Kindergarten (PT – EN) | Cascais, Portugal

Monitoring a group of children from various nationalities (between the ages of 2 and 6 years old) Assisting the teacher in the daily tasks.

2011 Master's Degree in Architecture (120 ECTS)

DETAILED PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

December 2018 – Till Date Tellin Shop

Yechte Consulting EU, Belgium

Tasks performed:

- Analysis of brand identity and graphical assets used on the website
- CSS class and coding standards
- Creation of multiple responsive layouts in Adobe XD
- Implementing feedback from the client to create the final solution
- Analysis of DOM structrure and CSS classes to guarantee best insertion of new elements

UX Kit

Tasks performed:

- Study case of the yechte company identity, target market, business direction and overall atributes
- Establishment of specific guidelines in graphic and coding guidelines (CSS)
- Creation of a living data base document (using Adobe Illustrator, In Design, Microsoft Word) that encompasses a set of rules and principles that future collaborators can follow.

Website Audit

Tasks performed:

- Creation of wireframing and diagrams to establish the information flow of the current website
- Testing of the interface for data collection (loading time, navigation between pages, overall design and coherence between pages, responsiveness,...)
- Production of final report listing current situation (positive and negative points), gathering of success cases to serve as references for improvement. Working in an Agile environment producing daily reporting using an online collaborative tool and digital Kanban board.

April 2018 – November 2018 Energie Plus Le Site

RGWiT Services SPRL, Belgium

Tasks performed:

- Creation of style guides and UI guidelines
- Design of the interface layout for desktop and mobile versions using Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD and Zeplin
- Design assets (icons, favicons,..) using Adobe Illustrator
- Unit Testing of the interface in front-end applications
- Presentation of solutions to clients and implementation of feedback

MiGroup We are a Welcoming Europe Movement

Tasks performed:

- Meeting with clients for the analysis of requirements and graphic guidelines previously implemented
- Gathering of references, definition of expectations and goals
- Design proposals and multiple assets (icons, favicon, og cards,...)
- Testing interface

Automobiles Gaité

Tasks performed:

- Meeting with clients for the analysis of requirements
- Gathering of references, definition of expectations and goals
- Design proposals and multiple assets (icons, favicon, og cards,...)
- Testing interface

Digital Illustrations for Website

Tasks performed:

Design illustrations with a consistent look and feel following the RGWiT branding

Customer Relationship Manager App for Yellow Pages Enterprise

Tasks performed:

- Research of similar products
- Defining the User Journey
- Wireframing and definition of interface concepts based on four main modules: New Project, Contacts, Calendar and Financial Balance
- Implementation of Google Material Guidelines and GDPR compliant components
- Prototype using Adobe XD

Vaping is Not Tobacco

Tasks performed:

- Creation of 3 design proposals
- Meeting and engagement with the marketing team
- Discussing graphic limitations within the ECI
- Design assets using Adobe Illustrator and Adobe Photoshop

Socar Shipping Agency – App for Tracking Cargo Shippings

Tasks performed:

- Analysis of previous versions, target market, research of similar products
- Definition of user journey
- Definition of interface concept, Wireframing
- Implementation of GDPR compliant components
- Implementation of modules such as user profile, announcement of vessel departures and arrivals, favourites, news feed, booking of new cargo and vehicle sales

Nizu - Logo Design

Tasks performed:

- Study of RGWiT branding guidelines
- Creation of several proposals to be shown and chosen amongst the team

June 2018 - July 2018

Birdlife International, Belgium

Natura Alert - Logo Competition

Tasks performed:

- Analysis of Birdlife mission, vision and history
- Study of Natura Alert app (beta) for definition of user profile and style guidelines
- Brainstorm, creation of logo concepts, drafting of proposals
- Preparation of screens and layouts to present 3 proposals for the final submission

April 2018 - August 2018

TRIAS, Belgium

Tasks performed:

- Analysis of client's requirements and data collected
- Definition of content structure with the client
- Compilation of data in a graphic format using Adobe Illustrator
- Presentation of results
- Implementation of feedback received
- Formation of client in inkscape.org (Open Source Software edition of vector files) for translation purposes

July 2017 - Dec 2017

Cozzis Casimiro Lda, Portugal

Tasks performed:

- Front desk management and welcoming clients
- Analysis of client's demands, project debriefing
- Development of 2D and 3D projects using Winner Design (production of renders and budgets)
- Presentation of proposals to clients